why is fuzzy on a wholesome why is Jonah
because it's rooted from sensuality and
an awesome thanks
by establishing mind this is how I
understand anyway establishing the mind
to the extent wait you sort of beyond
those things yeah theoretically that's
fine yeah so um what is then what what
is the principle of sensuality there is
then abandoned anjana and see you again
to charity
okay honestly seeing the seeing that see
the pain is pleasure for sure and how is
it possible what assumption is required
will you just keep seeing pain as
pleasurable you know get back
submitted something to do with
a second option was the perfect what's
the words the principle of assumption
any assuming sort of something outside
yes so as we said before you assume that
the pleasure is outside of your desire
yeah and the things is it in whatever
even if you don't specify where it is
you assume is outside of this presently
enduring unpleasant desire and that's
why it starts to well that's why you
induce a separate identity to their
desire desire this is the identity of
pleasure hence the assumption of sensuality if
hence the assumption of sensuality if
you were to see that doesn't matter the
extent of your pleasure is within the
painful designed us it's unpleasant you
will stop regarding in a separately
pleasurable yeah you can only see them
see it as pleasant see this pleasure by
seeing it's the same room from the pad
outside and I'm saying pain because it's
fully enclosed within the pain exactly
that is the principle there is a
principle sensuality yes and that is the
principle that you abandoned in the
first jhana and that's why theoretically
it is still possible to maintain some
ignorance despite developing the mind in
the first jhana
but it's highly likely that's what John
is in yourselves are very also it's
unlikely you would be abandoning the
wrong assumptions in principles without
a degree of understanding that's it's
correct contemplation right - tabla shman
contemplation right - tabla shman
cuz it's a liberation it's completely
undoing the assumptions now obviously
it's the fundamental wisdom in regard to
the nature of the assumptions they will
then keep you perpetually free from
those and if you haven't developed their
wisdom then if you're not established in
the jar and then these certain
assumptions might apply
again but even even so you could see how
how much less instruction a person who
has developed mine to the extent of the
first jhana how much less instruction
that person would need he noted to them
fully understand the nature of Madonna
so what do you think what is that there
is not necessarily unwholesome but it's
on the level of assuming it outside that
gets abandoned and thus establish the
first jhana by abandoning it of course
you'll be drawn from sensuality but more
specifically so not just that the
initial the initial establishment has
line dijanna yeah I was thinking it was about
dijanna yeah I was thinking it was about
putting yourself beyond sensuality yeah
yeah that's that's all result of it
right but on a most practical level well
what did the Buddha say what is the
thing that ceases in the first job okay
speech speech exactly and what is the
necessary base for speech well body well
know according to 1st jhana did it will
describe physically Charlie yeah so
you're thinking of Andrzej thinking and
exploring thinking and pondering isn't a
service so what is the necessary basis
for engagement with external essential
objects for the sake of chasing pleasure
what is the necessary base for that
what does it need to be they're enduring
in order for you to be making effort in
performing actions to avoid physical
sense objects I guess those okay but in
between like you can have thoughts
without needing to seek essentially what
is specifically tied to same-sex sensual
gratification what is the necessary
phenomenon that needs to be present
together for you to chase after yeah
desire desire exactly it's absolutely
and that's that the holding even if
things you're about to do are not
necessarily immoral or wrong if you're
doing them out of the desire they are
sensual yeah if you're not if you say to
them with this I there's no desire it's
the desire that determines the context
whether it's the assumption sensuality
or not that's why and that's why certain
things you cannot do without desire yeah
that's that's why you know if I like to
translate common sense desire sure
because it comes from with sure sure
sure yeah yeah yeah absolutely
it is molecular so back on the principle
what parallels can you draw them desire
is a necessary basis for sense objects
yeah they they're assumed to be pleasant
separately yeah outside of it how do you
think this yeah outside of the desire
separate to it after this how do you
think that relates them with the
thinking of ordering which is you know
can be quite neutral it's not routine
design and corresponding engagement of
speech at the stage breaking into speech
having thought and ponder and one breaks
into speech as a good attorney so that
would imply I'm thinking that I would
imply the
speech no no no no listen I said I said
from the start
desire is the necessary base for
sensuality that's one thing don't mix it
now with thinking and pondering a pen
speech I thinking and pondering is a
necessary basis for speech the principle
of desiring sensuality as in the
principle of assumption ah-huh how does
that compare to this but not like also
this is not an objective and sort of
permeated the the members know there's a
stays there a component free from
disaster date however there is a certain
principle that's in common to both yes
so desires the necessary basis for
engagement gratification if yes desire
and incidentally as you already said it
things incidentally but it was also
right answer as well just not what I was
asking in time can you have desire
without a thought of desire
no what is a desire unless it's your
mental thought and inclination
crazy so it's thinking and pondering
so it's thinking and pondering
effectively lobsters that we would say
desire is there so that can be thinking
and pondering with without a doubt yeah
yeah so as I said you always have to be
first jhana yes but you only have to
start in the reverse order
so thinking of ordering with desire is
the starting point yeah for an
unenlightened mind
yeah then thinking and pondering with
our desire is what you have to develop
yeah and you develop that when you stop
engaging with your tutors assumption of
separation thing something separate
something external something outside of
you because to that extent you're not
addressing it to that extent it's not on
you you have extent it's irrelevant to that
you have extent it's irrelevant to that
extent its secondary and the future is
yes and to that extent you remain
affected by it and so that and that it's
because it's over there it implies me
yes exactly reaffirms this whole thing
sure Joe so then desire and sensuality
and thinking pondering without desire
and speech what did it come what nature
do they share that won't determines the
other one okay the one is the necessary
basis for the adversity so ignorance say
ignorance of the necessary basis what is
that result like take the exact tactical
example yeah
ignorance did pleasure you project to
being sense objects is fully within the
context of your desire of it you cannot
be before after not even for a second
later yeah it's always within yeah so
you not knowing that what does the lack
of knowledge resulting after so why
would you be chasing after sense object
over there further pleasure
why do you think pleasures there
why do you think pleasure is that
because it's felt the Pleasant these
things well no these felt is pleasant
but why over there that you're clearly
feeling the prospect of sense of the
pleasant before you get to sense object
yet you're going to sense object but
you're feeling already Pleasant on
account of it yeah so why are you going
to send sultry them because you think
that's cuz you think it's that time yeah
cuz you think this pleasure I'm feeling
it's over there yes as ridiculous as it
sounds that is in its core of sensuality
that's which completely gratuitous
assumption yeah in that assumption is
the result of you ignoring the
fundamental context of nested
necessarily enduring desire for any
engagement even if you are not fully
conscious of your desire so whenever
you're engaging with sense objects for
the sake of pleasure that needs to be an
underlying container of desire yes that
is presently enduring unpleasantly but
it's a it's knowing that means bigger to
the separation induced by our assumption
won't be there anymore or certainly
won't be fueled not knowing that means
this separations they and the separation
is that the separation is both that the
pleasure is in the thing that I'm
chasing after you and is in the future
oh yeah of course it means and that
means it's always out there yeah of
course ironically even your assumption
of separation is within the context of
the present in do it in desire you can't
truly step outside of yes yeah that's
what once you fully understand that it
becomes inconceivable for you to think
in those terms in yeah so as you said
then what unites them is a necessary
basis so what is the necessary basis
sorry what is it what would what would
the result to so the necessary basis of
thinking and pondering necessary basis
for speech yeah
what would an ignorance of that context
of that order of that container what
would the result the result in result to
in regard to speak
the speech is somehow separate from your
thoughts in what manner can describe the
characteristics of separation like
I don't know
let's try this within speech you're
speaking now is that speech independent
of the simultaneously presently enduring
thinking pondering behind it like is
that speech before you thinking ponder
know is a speech after you've been
thinking fondant is the nature that
speech then not even a nanosecond after
the super king about okay but is that
speech it's my son remain well it has
its own tonight yeah exactly but which
is why people who then assume separation
yeah because it's not the same is
thinking upon the next other side so you
see there's a result of you think in
poverty in the same sense you see sense
the central pursuit as a result of your
desire yeah aiming at the result of your
desire so what's in common as I said
when asked initially to that that
separation assuming outside in regard to
the inside assuming it to be external
assuming space to be external to
thinking and pondering yeah yeah which
then makes ignorant of the domain of
thinking pondering which then makes you
incapable of establishing with this jump
because of that because you're putting
so you might be perfectly restrained in
the centrality but you still carry on
the same principle of the same
assumption in regard to the domain of
his speech so you say rather than saying
thinking and pondering through the
speech that's the only way you have to
see your speech within thinking and
pondering notice that you have to see
the possibility of speech within
thinking in the same sense of the same
possibility of your sense desires within
the pressure of the desire and there's a
thing oh when I'm speaking then when I'm
not speaking yet but there's a
possibility to break in their speech the
speech demands always and you assume
that possibility at least to be separate
yeah from the thinking from the
container to be outside of the container
of thinking upon the reading so you
fully understand this you will be
establishing the first jhana and you
will be dwelling in it
as the Buddha would say whether you walk
in sitting lying down going to the
toilet the man will be in that
establishment so hang on sir is so
that's what it said the speech ceases
speech in the first Johnny says yeah
because in order to you to speak you
have to maintain neutral it's not an
unwholesome assumption like sensuality
it's a neutral assumption of external
domain to the thought to the thought
that you engage with through speaking
and that assumption is like a function
outside of thoughts you have to step
outside of thought in order to speak now
what happens you never mind stepping
outside of the thought carries the
assumption of this is outside of the
thought yes once you better first John
is necessary for final knowledge for our
country or for being on a gun you need
to at least experience it in a sense of
not step outside on that fundamental
level to see that our assumption and
necessity of stepping outside in order
of practical speech are two different
things but not experiencing stepping outside of
but not experiencing stepping outside of
thought for speaking without assumption
for you it's assumed because of that
reason so because assumption comes first say
so because assumption comes first say
ignorance is beginningless so you can
it's possible to speak without without
assuming he does assuming the external
without giving it a separate identity
it's possible to speak without losing
the context or the necessary container
necessary basis of thinking and
pondering as a domain but even then you
have to turn away from thinking and
pondering in order to speak you need to
break into speech as you say so in the
first jhana you get to like sermon that
so that you understand or rather it
wouldn't result in you understanding the
death does not require an assumption of
an external world where the speech
occurs so can you say that
although right now you're not speaking
speech is there the domain of speech is
there that because there's always the
possibility for for you to break out of
the speech yes but more regularly that
possibility is also there as a
possibility because the mind hasn't been established
because the mind hasn't been established
on the domain of thinking and pondering
properly enough so that's what I'm
saying so that the possibility of speech
is not the same thing as thinking a
problem from public
no no it's within everything's within
thinking ponderings to certain thoughts
and certain Ponder's yes they can break
into speech they can turn away from its
own nature in order to speak if I were
to express it it's just the same as
saying it nothing can be experienced
apart from mentally has the kind of
mental phenomena well nothing can be
experienced outside of the container of
mental phenomena yeah they're different
aspects within that but there is nothing
separate to it as in external to it yeah
so like with like you know it's like so
thinking about pure matter yeah presents
itself as I thought but you could say
that so within so this this domain of
thinking and pondering hmm it is that's
why if you develop thinking pondering
rattling if you develop first jhana you
are freed from conceiving and if you
have any understanding of how principle
conceiving Zanu piranha they will be
more than enough for you to fully fully
understand it and free yourself entirely
so the speech ceases because you saw it
it's fully contained doesn't matter how
far how long how loud you might be
speaking how much even you have been
speaking how much you will be speaking
yeah it can never step outside of the
domain of thinking and wondering
required to be they're enduring
simultaneously with your speech but also
required for you to not think about it
in order to speak that's how you break
into speech you can't be thinking about
what you're speaking and speaking now
the speaking becomes you're thinking
about your speech yeah yeah which is why
you turn away from thinking which is why
it's neutral there's no problem with it
but there is a problem for somebody who
hasn't been freed from assumptions from
Adana because any principle of of putting
because any principle of of putting
second as first at first a second is the
principle that is then maintaining the
fundamental ignorance so you want to
learn how to speak without putting the
speech first and thought second yes
without forgetting maybe though the
refusing to speak ever again yeah
exactly cuz they don't stay within the
cuz they don't stay within the
possibility of spirit it's gonna be hard
for you to understand yeah exactly but
but said without kind of losing sight of
the necessary basis for last page so
speech ceases when you became when
you've developed full clarity in regard
to the nature of speech being always
within the container of thinking of
Andreea you dwell on that newly
clarified context long enough at least
for that time as a result of your
dwelling on that imperturbable nature
imperturbable order yes you become
unable to sort of even direct yourself
so to speak towards possibility of
speech hence the actual speech assist the
hence the actual speech assist the
actual speaker says because the speech
is there because you when you are within
the possibilities of saying something
yeah but whether you are saying
something whether you are abstaining
from speaking whether their
possibilities are all that is within the
presently enduring thinking and wanting
a boundary yeah yeah because for you now
you might say okay my thinking ponder is
Bennet but the possibilities of speaking
you still kind of retreated assumed as
belonging to the speech domain which you
gradually assumed to be external not as
you belong into the thinking of
pondering domain which is not an
external or internal it's just they're
exactly external internal becomes
defined when you externalize things with
your various assumptions then in return
that defines which is not external thus
that's my internal way me exactly and
this is a principle for all the journals
that's why is there is the modernist so
in the second jhana thinking and
pondering would cease
why because thinking and pondering has
been assumed external in regard to
what's then in the second jhana what's
necessary base for Joey
exactly a certain happiness agreeable
equanimity sort of agree ability of it
because there is not much movement
same principle then goes to the
immaterial establishments of the mind so
if they which like for example breathing
stops yah-hoo jhana because why because you do
yah-hoo jhana because why because you do
assume movement of the breath may be
external to the body yeah you tiny bit
you still assume it yeah failing to see
that how can they even how can any
notion of breath even be conceivable if
it's not defined entirely within the
body so you do this the subtlest of
assumptions are the ones like third
jhana for John but as I said of
assumption in its its assumption in its
nature of assuming external while it's
actually within it but it's not
assumption necessarily in in the in the
nature of containing ignorance and lust
in a version so as long so just want to
try for that so people don't know
assumption that's what as I said theoretically to
that's what as I said theoretically to
to Gina can develop Jana's yeah save me
and still remain ignorance like the
fundamental nature assumption yeah but
if if he like a petition develop Gianna
you could see how much work he already
done yeah he already undone all these
structural assumptions he understood
that he needs very little instruction
then so by all means develop the
understanding of Jonah's with or without
review but it's highly likely we'll be
able to develop it with other review
today because your notion of Janus is to
the instruction of the Buddha which ends
you you we will be sufficient familiar
so the word sees so when it's breathing
with ceases and fourth jhana you've
literally ceases so persons saying
they're not breathing but it isn't just
tell they're not breathing
it's that they've stopped yet the reason
they're able to not breathe is because
they stop assuming life to be external
yeah life which means breathing it
stopped yeah yeah exactly means he
stopped requiring external maintenance
oh that's why even the life in itself
it's within the same principle the
Buddha called it it's another necessary
basis but that basis is a bit out of
reach for everyone except some some
Buddha he can he can direct his
intentions toward that basis yeah as he
did does it
he's time for the targeted to die yeah
he relinquished the Isengard
it's the same principle that he has away
even then yet to it even then you have
to eat corrupted meat now strive to get
sick and so on but but that's that's the
point it's actually doesn't matter how
subtle you go how far you go how far you
surmount things the principle of
contained within container
yeah there has to remain so so say
that's what yeah you could also see it
from that level the principle is still
maintained if your body gets killed you
you know you haven't gone you didn't go
anywhere in a way your body's gone
certain aspect of your form is gone
yeah but the principles they maintain
you bound to the phone through these
gratuitous assumptions are still there
and that's the core of rebirth
you're not rebirthing anyway you're just
modifying the environment you're always
in literally because on that fundamental
level these all these assumptions that
keep that whole possibilities of these
different environments different lives
so it's all within the 500 so within the
principle of the tsunami external within
the internal all of it so it's just real
not even reappearing I think the mistake
you've disappeared it's actually what
you're living you're dying you in
between is the Buddha said you're reborn
are like yesterday today tomorrow there
is no greater mystery to that then
mystery between how was our yesterday
and what am i today and what will I be
tomorrow it's the same principle just
here point of view here enduring
enduring like this sitting like this
enduring in this yeah exactly subjected
to change subjected to various elements
that's it so when those elements changed
sufficiently next thing you know or not
know but you are an animal
yeah when those elements changed
sufficiently your their point of view
remains there that have a base remain
there o years old exactly and that's why
somebody remembers of previous life they
wouldn't give the similar it's like
somebody who came from one village to
the other village to the other villages
and then somebody in the last village
asking where you come from and he
remembers a village before in British
before yeah if you were truly traveling
through different bullets externally you
will have no recollection of it because
you will be outside it to yourself yeah
so cessation of speech then it's a
section of speech
how would you begin developing it so
normally start you know you know in a
broadest manner yes I normally well
normally well be the necessary
conditions can you develop cessation of
speech in company
oscy yeah no no can't spend some time
around inconceivable even if everybody's
inconceivable even if everybody's
perfectly silent you just would watching
defeat the possibility to talk to them
he's always that exactly so the domain
is people there's always there even if
you've said I'm not going to speak to on
you I'm really complement what my talk
to me exactly it's not a matter of
determination it's a method of still pertaining to
it's a method of still pertaining to
that domain that's assumed to be
external and now other people are just
reinforcing because you already have
four sets of notions about externality
of other people so good luck then fixing
it so you need to be physically
withdrawn even if you're not setting
curves like you need to be at least in
solitude very a possibility of being
affected by speech yes he's not there so
now it's on you knew so what would you
then do well
I guess acknowledge the possibility of
speech as being present
what does acknowledgment mean what does
that entail like
huh what do you mean by saying in ology
what would you like like he's driving
you like I guess I want to say like so
like you've got it's obviously it's
obviously gonna be seeing speeches being
fully enclosed within thinking and
pondering mm-hmm so how to do that yeah
by dwelling or thinking about money I
guess yeah but thinking pondering without
yeah but thinking pondering without
implying the possibility of speech
without simultaneously so ah so any any
any so basically what is the possibility
of speech
it's think it's a thought a thought but
it's a particular type of thought that
directs towards breaking the speech away
from itself for being a thought which is
are you telling us you're on your own
doing what you would naturally be
breaking out to speech when you're on
your own no but you would also will not
be thinking about the possibility nah
that's when you have a voice in your
head talking or song you can't get rid
of and so on
cuz you completely untrained yeah in
regards to the domain of the possibility
of speech which is the domain of speech
so there is an internal silence even if
but yet first you have to be silent
external of course yeah first you need
to be back to sensory strength
externally in order to understand the
perversion on the inside and free
yourself from sensuality so this is the
same so thinking sorry the possibility
of speech is thinking and pondering
sorry it's possible in the speech is
thinking abundant of particular nature
it's a particular name so what are the
characteristics of that thought of the
thought that particular thought which is
breaking it so got quiet now yeah and
think about possibility to say something
and I want you to tell me the
possibilities of that possibility of
saying something the characteristics of
a
mystics of possibility to say something
I guess it's like it's somehow like
stepping out I'm like well which one is
stepping out or okay so the possibility
to speech is about the possibility to
step out exactly okay yeah there's like
the possibility of going outside of this
yeah that's why you speak exists beak because
that's why you speak exists beak because
all right well you - but you say is
because you can yeah but there's the
thing now let's let's stay on this
possibility to step outside yes how do
you know that exactly
it's like possibility that I will get a
pleasure from touching this but I know
that while I'm not touching this exactly
well about that posit that possibility
of going out there is here not just that
would you even conceive any notion of
out there without this possibility
enduring so would you be able to
conceive the speech in act act of
speaking externally yeah without a
possibility to speak without having
thought and pondered with possibility of
breaking into speech would you be able
to speak no with that constitutes a hang
on the domain of speech is that already
given no that's the wrong way to go
around let's go that way again saddened
you have possibility to say something
the characteristics of that possibility
as you said that it implies the
possibility to go outside to see
accessory get step outside of thoughts
is it is it
so all this mental domain get something
so describe me now the characteristics
of the outside aspect of that
well they're separate from
what is that in its nature the notion of
outside how can you even talk about it
well yeah what is it like what is it
it's outside it's so like the notion and
you know what is it in its nature oh
it's it's it's it's manifested its that
its place what is it since nature what
it's doing what is it a notion of this
notion of that what is it well any don't
any notion what is the notion its
nature a thought I thought yeah so
within the pole which is already
thinking of on during possibility of
speech is already thought yes you have
another thought within that thought yes
it says that I'm not a thought since I
am outside of these causes that's it so
your notion of outside is an inside
thought so to speak and that's why there
is an assumption
not because of speech no because of the
principle of breaking into speech
turning away from you can turn away from
thoughts all you want and speak what you
want and still not assume the thought to
contradict itself as in this is outside
and I can only think that on the inside
so you can be free from assumptions and
still speak our on wouldn't go mute yeah
exactly so I'm not dwelling long enough
on the characteristic of outside within
your thoughts you continuously maintain
the notion of outside there's then
carried and perpetuated with your speech
that's effective ignorance so basically
this
speech the possibility of speech is
being the possibility of stepping
outside it's based upon listen no you
should say that this possibility of
speech is possibility of turning away
from thoughts
yeah but not stepping outside with
ignorance turning away from thoughts
means being outside but as I said I'll
tell you what do you realize well that's
already a thought so you can't be truly
outside yeah that's the only reason
you're outside is because you don't
fully understand you can't be outside
that's what I'm trying to say so so
there can be speech without assumption
yeah because you now you see that it's
quite possible to keep so you could
break out into speech but that breaking
out speak out into speech cannot take
you outside of the domain of thinking
and pondering because the whole domain
of thinking and pondering is completely
enclosed within the whole domain of
speech and the possibility of speech is
enclosed within thinking and pondering
in the same sense all of your physical
actions are enclosed within your mental
attention all your verbal actions are
enclosed within mental intentions so
then you wanna take a thought of outside
allow it to endure as depth which says
it's outside and see the whole thing
within the nature of being a thought and
that's how you become incapable of
assuming of maintaining good putana
of perverting the order because if you
realize that every single single example
that could possibly arise of going
outside can't possibly be outside no
that's for sure
that's why I said it many times to keep
saying it
[Music] / - Gianna which means he didn't have
/ - Gianna which means he didn't have
job as a time mm-hmm when they would've
left he said under the tree and said no
yeah first Jennifer's you know what is
first John and started reflecting on the
characteristics of the first jhana
and develop the footage on the second
jhana but reflecting on the
characteristics that he heard from the
guna and that's how I develop all the
John is that you got a patch of staring
at you no stones
I think no I think the Buddha would have
said instead of dwelling on these
factors characteristics of the first
jhana why don't you just watch it your
nostril yeah and it will happen to you
have a sense of this the overwhelming is
studies so joy you're gonna have then
somebody will tell you that was to John
yeah and then you will know it was to
John yeah tell you what cultures it you
were kind of so the point is it needs to
be understood here well at least
recognized on the right level right
level being level of the mind as in
thinking and pondering what is what is
your mind other than presence of a
thought so you have a possibility to
afterwards with your mouth and that's
fine however if you're ignorant of the
nature of that possibility the nature of
it being in us the nature with being a
Sankara the necessary basis the nature
it been a container that it cannot be
step outside then you committing to
uttering words with your mouth is then
you assuming somehow pertaining to this
external domain that has this separate
from the thinking and pondering of the
possibility of the speech they was there
throughout has to be there if you
suddenly for stop thinking while you
were about to say what you were saying
you will stop speaking exactly so since
by Savanti
it's called unification of mind yeah
that's it's calling paterberg oh it's
only perturb herbal in some majestic
mystical transcendental sense it's
imperturbable because you have restored
the right order that is now
imperturbable but definition like turn
something upside down
well now it's internal yeah because the
mind got established upon the right over
there soy de Zarate Kris and soy it is
not optional yeah that's the thing the
wrong border was established the
perversions were there because you
didn't realize they can't be there that
was the basis for them being there
that's why you're responsible for their
bhava for their being because the fully
assumed by you but can you say about
because it begins with thinking and
pondering this mental domain as being
that necessary basis that contained no
dude nothing can step outside of
absolutely even any assumption of static
so it's enough for the community
liberation jhana then understanding the
extent to that domain the scene as a red
slide it's it's more than enough for the
full uprooting of all this older like
master version delusional suffering I
can't remember the Sutra but people can
mention in the comments if they know the
reference where the Buddha says then for
the first which one spoken eyes I go to
the Kaiser good drinker had the first
John Riis like yeah busy says that a
Nogami been through from sensuality or
final liberation or higher sure sure
yeah which means you can get the right
view and everything else before that but
great if you get in on the basis of
Oceania it is very little work for you to do
it is very little work for you to do
between on being a so father sort of
Panama and another hand if you already
have developed mine to this
imperturbable order of the nature of
things what comes first is first oh
isn't it marvelous putting second that
which I was putting first and put it
first at which I was putting second
that's me
you can't create anything by the way
even I don't country of anything he just
undoes the mistake the perversion of the
old that it was completely traitors you
can't actually change the order you
can't actually have the external domain
of your speech independent of your
thought yep that's how you live in here
for eons and eons and eons how are you
doing because we read an assumption yeah
so you approve the assumption you have
seen the maker of the raft and the
rafters are destroyed and the maker of
the house saying that is to make all
these assumptions yeah
Katrina's little assuming external in
regard to this giving it a separate
identity which unit then defines you as
an identity and so on and so once you
stop assuming something external then
I'm just how'd you stop assuming
somebody stole by including whatever it
is if any thought any notion any kind of
something external by recognizing that
that has to be included within really
what the necessary basis which is what
so in this case where you're talking
right is thinking upon dream on the mind
with I don't say within the mind I lose
everything is in my mind which kind of
implies or then there are other things
that are outside of your mind
yeah but the thought of outside of your
mind well that's a thought which means
it's within my mind is surely
inconceivable when I think outside or
inside or both or neither or in between
or in Ovid on on the basis of the mind
being there they container of it the
container of the thought the reason why
I just brought my mind up is because I
know it is you know page to point
yeah but yeah yeah but you see think the
same principle can also be done I think
you like we're talking in the last talk
about the body yeah
so you can check that's why there are
all those different how did the comment
additional saying objects did yeah you
used to develop first John yeah yeah
come on Hanah
yeah it's the same things you can
understand the same principle you can
establish the same right order
and that's what Jonna will be then so
yes the body so you can use the public
as you're swimming outside of the body
how can you know that
I said you asked you the previous talk
whatever recorded economy yesterday
before well when you see things out
there if distantly yeah so how could
that Parker that thing even though it's
not exactly necessary basis that's right
here so basically you're seeing the eyes
seeing things
yeah in the only relationship you can
have with the world outside of your
senses is the relationship that gets
mirrored on to your senses yeah you
can't see things that mirror things on
to your senses you only say see the
mirror things on your senses and that's
only see the sense is affected by these
things yeah and then you assume those
are the things outside of these senses
and that's that's where you conceived
matter or misconceive any form of
conceiving outside as in conceiving the
elements conceiving the method as the
buddha said it's misconceiving ears and
so that's that applies to any notion of
something to a distant book or into also
in terms of time i'm yeah the future yes
again it's not here it doesn't before
later old new big small up-down matter
or feeling or intention of perception
method is there feeling is there so yeah
i have thoughts of past i'll stop
thinking stop thinking well that's
another thought yeah so you're saying
you think you're stop thinking while
you're thinking and you're actually
deluding yourself even further now you
think about past you plan about the
future how can you do that in any other
way except thinking right here right now
presently so it's not optional for the
to do is instead of you trying to
interfere with it and prevent you I must
stop lining or something no you must
stop acting carelessly on your plans but
that's a completely separate domain if
you choosing to act but thoughts of your
plans thoughts of your past are thoughts
that's all you're concerned about you
don't care the content of your
you care about it's a thought that's it
the thought is there yeah if the thought
is there anything that is in response to
that thought cannot be outside of the
container of that thought
hence the intentionality behind your
actions is like one of the most
fundamental and most practical things
you can develop even if you don't commit
to fall on practice in the drama yeah
resulting in that responsibility
transparency the confidence in strength
and virtue wisdom it will result in
wisdom right could you stop the vetting
the order on the blood of body speech
and mind cuz it's some pervert about not
knowing that no knowing that it's a
virgin and then you just keep acting out
of it so then including the
characteristic of outside of this
possible of these thoughts of
possibility of speaking while I'm not
speaking that's how you cease to speak
including the characteristic of outside
yes characteristic that is sort of
bundled with yeah there is sort of
implied in possibility of breaking into
speech possibility to break into outside
that last bit of outside you include as
within this domain of thinking abundant
develop that develop credit in regard to
that at that time that's the first job
at that time your sees you your speeches
ceased and then when you only break into
the sense that well you think that
you're you you know any possibility to
speak does not involve an assumption of
going outside inside if they're thinking
about exactly so then then you might
wonder so how can you speak ever again
afterwards once you on the assumption
but you can still speak without changing
my soaps without colors that's what I
mean you assuming outside is an extra step
you assuming outside is an extra step
yeah
that'll mean assuming outside is an
extension of the looking away from the
thoughts towards the speech but that's
it that's what it says ends but that's
hard to see so you just naturally assume
a better ending which is outside world
yeah and that's what you're responsible
for it because it's not there yeah so
turning away from thoughts in order to
speak is a necessary basis for speech
that's a necessary action behind the
speech turning away from thoughts with
ignorance assumes the arm I'm turning
away from thoughts from here I'm turning
over there and so if you stop going that
far you'll still you will still be able to
you'll still you will still be able to
speak without assuming external world of
speech yeah you you are temporarily
looking away from the thinking of
pondering that's the nature of speech
breaking into speech bones same with
body action but you you're that turning
away doesn't involve the kind of
assuming the separate domain where this
turning away will occur because that's
that's really that's contradiction in
terms so what do you need to do is approve the
so what do you need to do is approve the
assumption from it why do why why is
this assumption of outside so strong so
we're during so obviously because
there's some pleasure involved in this
option so of course episode I can there
is a pleasure in the nature of Madonna
yeah doesn't matter necessarily the content
doesn't matter necessarily the content
as in if it's a up or down about the
speech or Rupa Dona about self knows you
know it's about the outsiders don't act
it out I - yeah yeah there's something
about externality which in itself is
pleasant because it's beyond this pain
pretty much is beyond this situation
yeah or at least it allows possibility
to be beyond this situation and all of
that is oh yeah all of that is rooted in
you not wanting well rooted in you
feeling the pressure of the situation
yeah which you crave against which is why you
which you crave against which is why you
put once English as my you then engage
with assumptions and that is
beginningless gratuitous but
beginningless is the buddha said there
is no discernible beginning before which
a VJ wasn't there was no ignorance in
southern you became ignorant so that's
why they comes hand in hand not
expecting something outside or beyond
mechanics I say you can expect things
outside and then include your
expectation within the domain of thought
contained in it thank you literally with
this I have these expectations with with
manifestations of this necessary basis
these things are possible
it's 50 to embody his definition no I
was just trying to say that like that
know the extent to which you're
expecting something external outside is
to do with how your inability to
withstand what's present yes that's more
like now in the level of sensual
assumptions desire but when when you
have obviously kind of withdrawn
yourself from that the the expectation
of how external speech is it's not
necessarily corresponding to how much it
alone your thoughts or something like
that okay it's it's basically just a
another principle yeah that kind of fits
into your already existing assumptions
so you can see gets taken by that's why
once you bend the assumptions these
principles can still remain thinking
speaking but you won't be able to think
speaker act out of lust out of aversion
out of those perversions their direct
result of ignorance direct result of
assumptions chasing the pleasure chasing
the external or getting rid of the
whatever assuming the external to
basically overcome the unpleasant the
enduring pressure of the feeling you're
subjected to failing to say the Baxter
its failing to see that all will be
rooted in
you're craving against this feeling so
now when you're not speaking when you go
back to Cody you're not speaking
think about possibility to speak this it
it has to be done present you can be
careless you can't get distracted while
you're thinking about the possibility of
speaking but not speaking it's already a
form of mindful thinking or less
unmindful thinking because that's women
that we said beginning here you can you
cannot speak and still not being vagina
that's not yeah all you have to do why
you're not in German because the domain
of the the extent of this domain of
speech which includes possibility of
breaking into speech hasn't been
understood and has been stupid you can
be thinking about it but in order to
think about they want us to dwell on the
present possibility to speak to speak
and then start descending the kind of
gratuitous implication of outside help
which is a characteristic of that
possibility at the moment and then put
that characteristic within the
possibility not maintain its notion that
it's separate from anything outside of
it that's it so put that which you're
putting first put it secondly that's the
clearest description of how to write a
journal in the hood yeah you develop
that John is the necessary result not
like oh well do this technique in that
and then hopefully it will happen to you
and then you do all the meditation with
that implicit hope and desperately
looking at whatever is occurring is this
yeah is that teacher tell me
oh right having to interpreted by
somebody else that's why it's it's tied
in with understanding with clarity with
imperturbability